A Guide to the Jane Ellen Greene Papers, 1856-1937
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Jane Ellen Greene Papers, 1856-1937
The Library of Virginia
45120
2.275 cubic feet (6 boxes)
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Purchased.
Biographical Information
Jane Ellen Greene was born in Ireland on 5 August 1840. She was the daughter of Rev. William Greene (1807-1885) and Frances Whittle (1816-1897). She emigrated to the United States in 1872, and settled in Staunton, Virginia. Greene later moved to Martinsville, Virginia, where she died on 4 May 1931. She is buried in Oakwood Cemetery.
John Joseph Greene was born in Dublin, Ireland on 10 October 1848. He was the son of John Greene (1813-1889) and Charlotte Perry. He received his Bachelor of Medicine degree at University College Dublin, and later was a Surgeon-Lieutenant Colonel on the Army Medical Staff. He served in Egypt (1876), Afghanistan (1880) and Sudan (1884-1885). John Joseph Greene died at Greystones, County Wicklow, on 18 August 1899. He is buried in Glasnevin Cemetery in Dublin.
Scope and Content
Papers, 1856-1937, of Jane Ellen Greene (1840-1931) of Staunton and Martinsville, Virginia, including correspondence and subject files, and also genealogical research files on the Greene family compiled by John Joseph Greene (1848-1899) of Ireland.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Correspondence and Subject Files.
II. Genealogical Research Files of John Joseph Greene.
Contents List
- Series I. Correspondence and Subject Files, 1856-1936., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 1-3)
  The bulk of the correspondence covers the years 1900-1906, and includes letters from friends and family in Norfolk and Martinsville, Virginia, and England and Ireland. The subject files contain clippings, diaries, financial records, greeting cards, and other material.
  - Accounts and Receipts. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bank Statements, 1918-1925. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificate - Chautauqua Literary and Scientific Circle, 1891. (Box 6)
  - Check Register, 1924-1925. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - C.P. Kearfott & Son. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Clippings. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1868-1902. (Box 1, Folder 6-20)
  - Correspondence, 1904-1929. (Box 2, Folder 1-16)
  - Correspondence, 1935. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, undated/no year. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Diary, 1856-1857. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Diary, 1883-1886. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Diary, 1901. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Greeting Cards. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Hair Sample - Georgina Frances Greene Anson. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Ireland - Historical Notes. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Poetry. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Promissory Notes. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Virginia Furniture Company, 1922-1926. (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Series II. Genealogical Research Files of John Joseph Greene, 1892-1899., Extent: 3 boxes. (Box 4-6)
  The genealogical research files on the Greene family were compiled in the 1890's by John Joseph Greene (1848-1899) of Scart, County Limerick, and Drumgorey, County Waterford, Ireland. In some cases, they also include later notations made by Jane Ellen Greene. John Joseph Greene had a volume privately printed shortly before his death in 1899 entitled Pedigree of the Family of Greene, Formerly of Greenville, Low Grange, and Newtown House, Co. Kilkenny, Moorestown Castle, Co. Tipperary, Old Abbey, Co. Limmerick. The files contain his notes and extracts from census records, chancery and exchequer case files, deeds, newspapers and other published sources, marriage records, parish registers, military records, obituaries, and wills from materials in the Office of Arms, record and probate offices, Registry of Deeds, Trinity College, and the National Library of Ireland, and also the Public Record Office, the British Museum, and Somerset House in London. There are also genealogical charts, pedigrees, and tombstone inscriptions. It is unknown when Jane Ellen Greene acquired John Joseph Greene's files. Their grandfathers were half-brothers.
  - Boer War - Timeline. (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Census. (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chancery Bills, Decrees, etc.. (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Charts. (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Charts. (Box 6)
  - Correspondence. (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Deeds. (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Distribution of Property of Jane Ellen Greene. (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Dundas. (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Exchequer Bills, Judgments, Decrees, etc.. (Box 4, Folder 10-12)
  - Exchequer Bills, Judgments, Decrees, etc.. (Box 6)
  - Gentleman's Magazine. (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Greene, Eliah. (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Greene, Godfrey. (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Greene, John (1807-1883). (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Greene, John Joseph (1848-1899). (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Greene, Joseph. (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Greene, Joseph (b. 1711). (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Greene, Joseph (1746-1830). (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Greene, Michael (d. 1777). (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Greene, Thomas (son of Capt. Godfrey Greene). (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Greene, Maj. William (1748-1829). (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Incumbered Estates. (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Kilmanahan Castle. (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - King's Inn Society. (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Marriages. (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Military. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Notes. (Box 5, Folder 12-14)
  - Miscellaneous Notes. (Box 6)
  - Moorstown Castle. (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Mortimer. (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper Abstracts. (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Nuttall. (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Obituaries. (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Parish Registers and Returns. (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Petitions. (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Poetry/Verses. (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Poulter. (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Powers of Attorney. (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Published Sources (Abstracts). (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Reminiscences of Jane Ellen Greene, 1896. (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Rents. (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Search Applications and Inquiries. (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Tombstone Inscriptions. (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Tombstone Inscriptions. (Box 6)
  - Wilde. (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Wills. (Box 5, Folder 31-32)
  - Wills. (Box 6)